# Esteban de Jesus Solis Rivera

Cellphone: +52 8781500418 · E-mail: <a href="mailto:stban\_2698@hotmail.com">stban\_2698@hotmail.com</a>

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/esteban-de-jesús-solis-rivera-1920a772/

#### **Profile**

Engineer with experience in projects such as ASAP, Netcool, and Nokia FlowOne. Specialized in identifying and addressing client needs using technologies. Worked closely with multidisciplinary teams and external clients to deliver effective solutions to complex problems.

#### **Education**

### Universidad Autonoma de Coahuila, México

August 2017 - August 2022

B.S. Physics Engineer | GPA: 3.5

- Thesis Laureate: "Kinematic study of the simple pendulum by video analysis technique and comparison by numerical simulation"

## **Professional Experience**

#### Integssoft

### **Solution Engineer- Oracle ASAP**

February 2022 – November 2022

- Develop the solution according to the solution proposed by the architect
- Implementation of the solution
- Test the solution
- Integration of the solution
- Ensure the proper compliance with agreements with the client

### **Solution Integrator – IBM Netcool**

November 2022 – January 2023

- Acquire and apply technical skills in Netcool, DB2, DevOne NPM, Cloud Pak for Watson IOPs, and SevOne Network Performance Management.
- Participate in the implementation and maintenance of Netcool-based solutions.
- Collaborate in the design and configuration of DB2 databases to optimize system performance.
- Implement and manage network performance solutions using DevOne NPM and SevOne Network Performance Management.
- Utilize Cloud Pak for Watson IOPs to enhance automation and operational intelligence.
- Ensure integration and compliance of implemented solutions with client requirements and service agreements.

## Solution Integrator - Nokia FlowOne

January 2023 – January 2024

- Measure current activation capacity and forecast future needs to increase the capacity of the activation solution.
- Create and maintain deployment, operation and maintenance routines.
- Monitor the system and control its performance.
- Manage statistics and perform performance data collection and analysis, taking appropriate short-term actions to ensure optimal performance.
- Establish SLAs and KPIs based on assessment of current activation capacity of FlowOne environments and in line with needs and installed infrastructure.

### <u>Developer – Nokia FlowOne</u>

January 2024 – Present

- Analysis of new requirements to develop
- Define type of development
- Develop the package release.
- Gather detailed information and requirements
- Create the elements to deploy
- Develop the software items
- Execute routines to maintain the functionality of 8 environments built on AWS.

### **Skills and Languages**

- **Languages:** English (Advanced), Spanish (Native)
- Software: Microsoft (Office, Excel, PowerPoint, Visio), Java, Python, C++, HTML, Software Design, SQL, Neo4j, VMware, Nokia FlowOne tools, Eclipse, Linux, Backend, Git, Jira, Netcool, DB2, DevOne NPM, Cloud Pak for Watson IOPs, SevOne, AWS.
- **Skills:** Leadership, Teamwork, Adaptability, Resilience, Innovation, Willing to learn, Organization, Customer satisfaction, Technical support service, Project delivery, Technology implementation, Incident resolution